Immortal invisible God Faithful One
You are my King Invisible God
Great and Mighty One
There is none like You
For You are God all by Yourself
Forever You are the same
There is none like You
You are God all by Yourself
Forever You are the same
There is none like You
Thank you.
You may have your seats; thank you.
Glory be to God.
Hallelujah.
(Amen.)
Faith requires us to speak them before we see or feel them.
You have to begin by believing, confessing and acting on God’s Word.
Then, you can bring Jesus on the scene, by believing.
This is what our faith requires – believing, confessing and acting on what?
On God’s Word.
You can bring Jesus on the scene, instantly.
It means you are not alone on your seat.
That you are sitting, looking – to many, you are not talking but your faith is talking.
I want to hear what your faith is saying because the words you speak determine the life you enjoy.
The words that are going on in your heart determine the life you enjoy.
Tell your neighbour.
(The words that are going on in your heart determine the life you enjoy.)
No, I don't know what you are saying.
You are sitting quietly but your faith is talking.
I'm saying: what is going on in your heart determines the life you enjoy.
Tell your neighbour.
(What is going on in your heart determines the life you enjoy.)
That is, the words you speak determine the life you enjoy.
They say, "I'm sitting down, I'm not talking."
Who told you you were not talking?
Something is going on.
"Look at this man. What is he saying? Hmm."
A lot is going on in your heart - it determines the life you enjoy next.
The words a man speaks create the blessing or curses in his way.
The reason is that your mouth is a revealer of the belief in your heart.
What is going on in your heart?
Something is going on – you are saying something; you know you have no control.
If I am not talking, my faith is talking.
Tell your neighbour.
(If I am not talking, my faith is talking.)
If I am not moving, my faith is moving.
(If I am not moving, my faith is moving.)
If I am not looking, my faith is looking.
(If I am not looking, my faith is looking.)
Just close your eyes and say, "I'm not looking, I can't see anything." - your faith is looking.
You say you are sleeping.
You faith is alive.
That is why if anyone comes to you in the dream...
Later I say, "Oh. It was a dream. I'm not talking, I'm not going to talk." - your faith is talking.
"I'm not praying. I'm not going to pray. I don't believe. I'm not going to pray."
Who told you are not praying?
How will you live next?
"I'm not going to pray" - they say your brother doesn't pray.
Who told you your brother doesn't pray?
His heart is saying something.
If you want to know what a man’s heart is saying, the next life will tell you.
Not now, next will tell you.
When a man suddenly falls on the floor...
Before that falling there was a thought that was going in his heart, "I hope I will not fall. I will fall. I will not fall.
I feel dizzy."
Before you know it you find yourself on the floor.
Sometimes, for you to know that it is not possible for you not to talk -
if you are not talking your faith is talking.
Sometimes, you would be just sitting down; something will be telling you,
"That my brother Kenneth is coming; he will be coming now. He will come today."
Before you know it you see brother Kenneth.
Only you will say, "This is what is going on in my heart."
Also if it is evil, you sit and say, "Ah, this vehicle seems - it will have an accident."
Only you, nobody knows you are talking about that.
Before you know it - an accident, "This is what was going on in my heart."
Say, “If I am not talking, my faith is talking.”
If I am not praying, my faith is praying.
What kind of faith?
Is it faith in faith or faith in the finished work of our Lord, Jesus Christ?
That will determine the life you enjoy.
If I am not talking, my faith is talking.
That is why sometimes - I stop praying because I want you to hear what I'm going to say.
I say, "In Jesus' name" because I want you to hear me.
After that "In Jesus' name", everyone will see me stretching my hand, and they get healed.
In the past they said, "This man does not mention the name 'Jesus'. He doesn't call the name 'Jesus' -
we don't know whom he is calling."
OK, Pharisees and Sadducees, “In Jesus’ name…”.
By the time I do that for ten people, I will get tired.
I have employed flesh in calling the name Jesus.
We employ much flesh to the things of the Spirit.
Once you light a candle, it is lightened - just place it.
So, you cannot light the candle, and light it again... no.
Since it is not quenched, it is not off.
You just light a candle - that is the name of Jesus.
But if it is not lightened, you continue to light it...
Once you want to pray for four people here; in the face of sister you say, "In the name of Jesus",
and you know Jesus hears you - He will continue to follow you to do the rest.
It is when you know Jesus...
The SCOAN Sunday Service
It is when you know Jesus, and He does hear what you are saying; you say, "In Jesus name - be healed"...
Because you don't believe Jesus has heard you.
Our mouth is a revealer of the belief in our heart.
There is power in our mouth but belief in our heart is released by faith.
The belief in our heart is released by faith and faith requires us to speak before we feel or see it.
The words we speak determine the life we enjoy.
What life are you enjoying?
This is the reason when we say, “In Jesus’ name”,
and another man says, “In Jesus’ name”, we see different results -
some idle, some meaningless, some oftentimes destructive.
Some will say, "In Jesus' name" - the result is meaningless.
Other will say, "In Jesus' name" - the outcome is idle.
Another people will say, "In Jesus' name" - oftentimes it is destructive.
What is the cause of this?
If the words you speak in prayer, preaching or teaching are not according to the Word of God,
are not according to the Spirit of God,
they oftentimes remain idle, meaningless and destructive.
If they are not according to the Word of God,
if the are not according to the Spirit of God, they remain idle, meaningless, oftentimes destructive.
You just say... when you want to sleep you say, "In Jesus' name I pray, Lord...".
You now open the Bible and pray.
In that night the demon will come and wake you up and start beating you.
He will even carry the Bible you placed on the bed and he will hit you with it, "What are you saying?"
By the time you wake up you say, "Ah. I pray, I call the name 'Jesus' and I open the Bible;
and this is a serious nightmare. Why demon is still fighting me?"
Because your prayers are not according to the Word of God, not according to the Spirit of God.
And the Bible says that the Spirit will be released to the degree we stand in reverence of His Word.
Tell your neighbour.
The Spirit will be released to the degree we stand in reverence of His Word.
I cannot hear you.
(The Spirit will be released to the degree we stand in reverence of His Word.)
The Spirit will be released to the degree we stand in honour of His Word.
Again.
So, if you now stand to say, "Jesus... Help me, Jesus. In Jesus' name"...
There is the language of today and the language of the Bible.
If what you are saying is not the language of the Bible,
I mean, not according to God’s Word, not according to the Spirit of God,
it will remain idle, meaningless or oftentimes destructive.
You will invite demons; that will invite demons to come and attack you.
Because if anywhere demons hear the name Jesus they want to...
They will just look, "Who is calling Jesus?"
And if they know there is no authority; and you are not calling the name 'Jesus' according to His Spirit,
not according to God's Word - they will jump on you.
This is what happened to seven sons of Sheva.
They said, "Jesus we know, God of Paul we know. Who are you?"
Because they realized that the name 'Jesus' they were calling was not according to His Spirit,
was not according to His Word.
They attacked them.
Many of us have been attacked, if the name is not according to His Word, or according to His Spirit -
you will be attacked.
"I call the name 'Jesus'. I believe in Jesus" - but not according to His Spirit, not according to His Word.
There is what we call, "language of today" and "language of the Bible".
The Spirit will be released to the degree we stand in honour of His Word; that is God's Word.
So, you can see now the reason why you have to be genuine; you have to be properly born-again.
There are many claiming to be Christians, all over the world.
You see them and keep asking yourself, "What is wrong?"
No, if your Christianity is not according to His Word, according to His Spirit;
my brother, your life will remain meaningless, idle, and many times attacked.
That name 'Jesus'; when you call it...
Whoever calls that name; whether you have the right to call that name, according to Spirit,
or according to His Word,
or you don't have any right to call it - you are just calling the name because other call that name -
satan always, "Ha! 'Jesus' - who is the person?"
He wants to know by what authority, meaning - are you calling the name according to His Word?
Who gave the right to call that name?
Are you calling the name according to His Spirit?
We can now see where our problem is coming from.
Our problem is coming from, "We are not Christians according to His Word.
We are not Christians according to His Spirit."
You can only be a Christian according to His Spirit.
You must be led - that is what I mean.
No one can say, “Jesus is Lord”, except by what?
By the Spirit!
It means you must be led to be a Christian.
No one can say, “Jesus is Lord”, except he is led, helped, guided by the Spirit.
This is why there is a fashion all over; we have religious people and we have Christians - there is a difference.
Christians / religious people.
There is a difference - the difference is just that: as a Christian you must be led by the Spirit.
You can start now; and how do we start this?
Yes; begin to meditate over the verses.
Not thinking about the verses; thinking is different from meditation.
You can only think about your challenges, problems, debts,
but when you talk of meditation you talk of your heart.
You mean devotion.
If not, many of us will get there, before we know we are not Christians.
And I don't want you to get there, before you know you are not a Christian.
With what we are seeing in the world today, it is so difficult to actually know who is Christian.
It is so difficult.
Because ceremonies, everything...
The church have been taken over by ceremonies.
You will be shocked.
It is so difficult; only Spirit of God can tell you, "This is Christian and this is religious man." - you don't know.
It is so difficult.
I don't want you to get there, before you know you are not a Christian.
Everywhere ceremonies, according to the syllabus, table or program - that is not Christianity.
The Church of the Holy Spirit should be next, not now.
Whatever we are doing in the Church of the Holy Spirit should be next, not now.
But today, now is the church; we know we want to do, read, sing - everything is in the syllabus
how things should be - conventions.
The Spirit inspires us from time to time, from moment to moment; telling us next.
Sometimes, we get loosed, disconnected; we don't know what to do next.
That will attest to our fitting; if you fit or you don't fit - you can know.
But how do you know if you fit, when what you want to do is already on the paper?
It is programmed, you just need to read it.
You can know if you fit.
I take you back again.
The Spirit of God will be released to the degree you stand in reverence,
I mean, in honour of His Word.
How do you honour His Word?
How do we honour His Word?
The Word of God must be integral – that is, part of you.
It stays here and later goes there.
It must be in your heart by meditation.
By meditation, your heart can act upon the Word.
Heart means your spirit.
That is, your spirit acts upon the Word by meditation.
When your spirit acts upon the Word, it begins to influence your character and behaviours.
"I don't want to smoke" - you can only stop that smoking when the Word acts upon your spirit; it will stop you.
But if the Word has not yet acted upon your spirit, and you say you want to stop smoking;
you will stop for a while.
After some time, you start in a big way.
By meditation, our heart acts upon the Word.
That is, your spirit acts upon the Word; that is joined, immersed.
When that happens, it begins to influence your conduct, your character.
What you say, "I cannot stop smoking" - you just find that smoking stopped,
because that Word has acted upon your spirit.
Sometimes you say, "I don't know; I've been trying to stop. I'm a child of God. I've been coming to church.
They have prayed for me."
The prayer will not do that.
"They have prayed for me" - to build your character.
Prayer cannot do anything if the prayer is not offered according to His Spirit, His Word.
So please, let us be genuine, OK?
Because sometimes you just begin, continue to fake yourself.
And you don't even know.
You will not even know; that is why I don't want us to get there before we know.
It will be too late, to get there before we know.
Ignorance is not an excuse.
We have so much wisdom, knowledge about the Bible but that knowledge
does not seem to be according to His Spirit, not according to His Word.
You will preach it, teach it; very good teacher, when you are give a mic to preach here... he is a good preacher.
You may be a good preacher but not according to His Spirit.
Tell your neighbour, "You may be a good preacher but not according to His Spirit."
That is, the presence of God is the Spirit.
The presence of God in what we are saying is that Spirit.
You can talk without the presence of God, "Jesus!"; people will say, "Oh my God - it is a good preacher" -
not according to His Spirit.
So, now, I want to leave you here.
The way out: meditation.
When we say 'meditation';
take more of me, oh Lord Jesus; give me more of You, of Lord Jesus.
When you are saying this; even your body will not move.
Nobody will know what you are saying.
Take more of me; give me more of You – more of Your obedience, more of Your kindness,
more of Your purity, more of Your faithfulness, more of Your holiness.
Take more of me, Lord and give me more of You.
This is what you should engage your heart in.
If you don’t engage your heart, your heart will engage itself.
Engaging your heart; begin to pray at the same time as you hear me, "What this man is saying?
Give me the grace to do it, to practice it.
Take more of me, Lord. Give me a hearing heart."
This is what you should engage on.
If you don’t engage your heart, your heart will engage itself.
You have to engage your heart in sowing to the Spirit.
Give me a hearing heart, Lord.
This is it.
When you are saying this, automatically your heart will act upon the Word I am speaking to you.
The heart doesn’t just act upon the Word without the grace.
While you are saying that, your heart will act upon the Word and when the heart acts upon the Word,
you will suddenly find your character and behaviour changing.
What you felt you couldn't stop; you will start stopping them.
Take more of me, give me more of You - give me a hearing heart.
So, you create a habit; for you to be great in the Lord you must have a habit.
It means; the time for yourself, the time to meditate on the Word of God.
You talk of prayer...
Prayer cannot work without your spirit joining itself to God’s Word.
Tell your neighbour, “There’s no prayer without your heart acting upon the Word.”
This is what we are taught today, "Prayer is the key. Prayer is the master-key."
It is master-key, when your heart acts upon the Word it becomes prayer.
Look at what I said.
I said to you that the Word you speak determines the life you enjoy, if the heart acts upon the Word.
Take note of that; my heart must act upon the Word.
This is what I mean by;
the Spirit will be released to the degree we stand in reverence of His Word.